Mss.Ms.Coll.115
American Philosophical Society
Kane Family Papers
1745-1955
Mss.Ms.Coll.115
American Philosophical Society
56.0 lin. feet
A collection of letters, legal papers and financial records of three generations of the prominent Philadelphia family. Spanning 1745-1955, detailed are the legal cases and political advocacy work of John Kintzing Kane (1795-1858), Robert Patterson Kane (1827-1906), and Francis Fisher Kane (1866-1955). Also includes correspondence, architectural drawings, and photograph albums of the Cope family. Robert Patterson Kane's daughter Eliza Middleton Kane (1863-1952) married the Philadelphia architect Walter Cope (1860-1902) in 1893. The APS papers of Elisha Kent Kane are in call no. B K132.
Various authors
Bache, A.D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867.; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891; Bartram, John, 1699-1777; Chesapeake and Delaware Canal Company.; Cope, Eliza Middleton Kane, 1863-1952; Cope, Walter, 1860-1902; Girard Bank.; Indian Rights Association.; Kane, Francis Fisher, 1866-1955; Kane, John K. (John Kintzing), 1795-1858; Kane, Robert Patterson, 1827-1906; Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1822-1883; Peale's Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.).; Saint George Society -- Trials, litigation, etc.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
- Series I. John Kintzing Kane, 1800-1892; Letters concerning Kane's career as a Philadelphia lawyer and Pennsylvania politician. He was Judge of the U.S. District Court in Pennsylvania, 1846-1854. There is much professional correspondence, as well as a lot of family material, especially concerning his son Elisha K. Kane. The letters with George Mifflin Dallas and Francis R. Shunk are especially rich for state politics. There is some concerning support for Alexander D. Bache's service in the U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
  Biographical/Historical note
  John Kintzing Kane (1795-1858, APS 1825) was a Philadelphia lawyer, City Solicitor, federal judge, Pennsylvania Attorney General and a member of the State Legislature. Although elected to the Legislature as a Federalist, he later worked as a Democrat, supporting the election of President Andrew Jackson and writing in support of Jackson’s opposition to the Second National Bank. Kane was best known for his work as a federal judge. Kane’s most controversial decision came in 1856, when he jailed a Philadelphia Quaker for failing to produce a fugitive female slave and her two children for the court. Despite a reputation as a ruthless politician, Kane had an abiding commitment to the public welfare that led him to labor on behalf of the Presbyterian Church, the blind and for the promotion of science, the arts and education. Kane was born in Albany, New York on May 16, 1795, the son of merchant Elisha Kane and Alida Van Rensselaer. The family moved to Philadelphia in 1801 after the death of his mother. In 1807 his father remarried Elizabeth Kintzing of Philadelphia. Fondness for his stepmother and the desire to distinguish himself from several cousins of the same name led Kane to adopt her maiden name as his middle name. John received his early education in boarding schools outside of Philadelphia. In 1810 he entered Yale University, graduating in 1814. Having long desired to pursue a legal career, Kane read the Law in Joseph Hopkinson’s office beginning in the spring of 1815. He was admitted to the bar on April 8, 1817 and afterward began practicing in Philadelphia. In April 1819 he married Jane Duval Leiper with whom he had seven children. Five years later Kane campaigned for the Pennsylvania Legislature as a Federalist and was seated in 1824; however, he went back to Philadelphia in 1825 to work as an attorney and board member of the Chesapeake and Delaware Canal Company. Although a Federalist in the final days of that party, he was Democrat in all but name and supported Andrew Jackson for president in 1828. He campaigned actively for Jackson, raising funds, coordinating meetings and writing a nationally circulated pamphlet entitled Candid View of the Presidential Question. After Jackson’s election he also wrote in support of Jackson’s opposition to the Second National Bank, causing enmity between himself and the Bank president Nicholas Biddle. In 1828 Kane also supported the Democratic candidate in Philadelphia’s mayoral race with the result that he became City Solicitor. In July, 1832 Jackson appointed him to a commission on spoliation claims after the 1831 Convention of Indemnity with France, and Kane published the substance of that body’s work. Kane remained a key figure in Pennsylvania politics in the 1830s and 1840s. In December 1838 he helped to lead the campaign to unseat two illegally elected Whig state senators in the struggle known as the Buckshot War. He was again active in the state and national elections of 1844, authoring pamphlets, delivering speeches and organizing the Democratic party in Pennsylvania. The reward for his efforts in the successful gubernatorial campaign was appointment as Pennsylvania’s Attorney General in January 1845. In June 1846 President James K. Polk appointed Kane a federal judge for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania of the United States District Court, a position he held for the rest of his life. His most controversial decision was in 1856, when he sentenced a Philadelphia Quaker to jail for failing to produce a female slave and her two children. This decision exacerbated the controversy over the Fugitive Slave Act. A religious conservative involved with the Presbyterian Church, in 1837 Kane served in the Church’s General Assembly as a member of the “Old School” and voted to sever ties with the denomination’s New School synods, who favored revivalist methods. Kane was also involved in cultural and intellectual pursuits. He joined the American Philosophical Society in 1825, served as secretary from 1828 to 1848, vice-president from 1848-1857 and president from 1857 until his death. He served on the board of the Academy of Fine Arts, was vice-president of the Institution for the Instruction of the Blind and a trustee of Girard College and vice-provost of the Law Academy of Philadelphia. Kane is best remembered as a federal judge, but was also influential as a political strategist and writer. His skills and support won him the gratitude and respect of two American presidents and many Pennsylvania officeholders. Kane also had a reputation for political ruthlessness. He was remembered by some as a man of ability, acuteness, some learning, [and] plausibility, but... without moral principle.” He died in Philadelphia on February 21, 1858.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition note
  Presented by Mrs. Joseph C. Aub, Dr. Oliver Cope, Thomas Pym Cope, and Mrs. Thomas P. Hazard, 1968-1974, children of Walter Cope and Eliza Middleton Kane Cope.
  Arrangement note
  See also Series II, VIII, IX, and X.
  Early American History Note
  Early American History note The John Kintzing Kane Papers is a large collection containing the correspondence, legal papers, and financial records of this prominent Philadelphian. The collection touches on a wide range of subjects of both local and national interest.
  Correspondence: The correspondence contains letters written to and from many of the most prominent figures in Philadelphia and the nation. There is an interesting set of letters from James Buchanan from the 1830s and 1840s, dated from Buchanan’s home in Lancaster and Washington discussing politics and current affairs. There are large collections of correspondence from Franklin Peale, Henry Gilpin, and especially Francis Shunk, governor of Pennsylvania. There is also some correspondence relating to Alexander Dallas Bache, including letters to President John Tyler recommending him. Other notable correspondence includes letters from/to Daniel Webster, Martin Van Buren, and Washington Irving. There is also extensive family correspondence, including Elisha Kent Kane. Finally, there are documents that provide insight into the operation of the Democratic Party, with numerous letters and other documents from county organizations and partisan associations to Kane. In addition to the personal correspondence, there are documents relating to Philadelphia institutions. These include papers dealing with the disposition of the John Bartram Estate, the financial records of the African Methodist Church in the 1820s, documents dealing with the Farmers and Mechanics Bank, the APS, and the Philadelphia Museum (specifically, the sale of its building to the APS). There is also a large folder on the Indian Rights Association, although this dates to 1892.
  Perhaps the richest portion of the collection is Kane’s own papers, which consist of essays and other documents that touch on a wide range of subjects. There is a note on the early members of the Junto, notes for a biographical profile on G.M. Dallas, a eulogy of Robert Patterson, documents on Democratic politics, a series of manuscript essays on subjects such as nurseries (that provides insight into how early childcare operated), prison reform, and on exploration, a historical essay on English aggression in Honduras, which discusses the history of Latin America, a long essay on Hamlet (that carries “not to be lent or shown” on its cover) discusses the author’s interpretation of Hamlet’s character, citing sections of play and dissecting their meaning, and finally a series of documents on Democratic presidential politics for the 1844 election. (See also Series IX and X)
  Bancroft, George, 1800-1891; Buchanan, James, 1791-1868; Cadwalader, Thomas; Caldwell, Thomas; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865; Green, John P.; Grier, Robert Cooper, 1794-1870; Grinnell, Henry, 1799-1874; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857; Kane, John Kintzing, Jr.; Leiper, William J.; McAllister, Richard; Miller, Jesse; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854; Patterson, Robert, 1802-1872; Phillips, Henry M., (Henry Myer), 1811-1884; Polk, James K., (James Knox), 1795-1849; Purviance, John N.; Robinson, Henry Mauris, 1868-1937; Saunders, R. M.; Snowden, James R.; Tilghman, Benjamin, 1785-1850; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862; Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852; Wharton, Francis, 1820-1889; Woodward, George W., (George Washington), 1809-1875; Antebellum Politics; Arctic regions -- Discovery and exploration -- American.; Business and Skilled Trades; Early National Politics; Family Correspondence; Law; Marriage and Family Life; Pennsylvania History; Pennsylvania--Politics and government; Philadelphia History; Political Correspondence; Social Life and Custom
  - Abercombie, Mrs. to Gov. Francis Shrunk, 1845 November
  - Acheson, A.W. to John K. Kane, 1845 November-1846 January
  - Adams, James, 1825 September 14
    Scope and Contents note
    Certification of birth of Thomas Calwell.
  - Adams Express Company, 1857 November-1858 January
    Receipts.
  - African Methodist Episcopal Church of Philadelphia #1, 1820-1824
    List of contributors and contributions: 2 liabilities and payment - Trustees Receipts for payment of ground rent 182?-1823. Accounts 1820,1823. Account of Bond to Watson Bunting 1823,1824. Expense and building payments, received 1824. Bill and receipts: Cunningham, J.H. 1820 Aug 9, Sept 12 Stephens, Fullman 1821 Nov 17 Bunting, Watson 1820-1822 Nutt, William and Carpenter 1824 April 20 J. Castles Potts, Cyrus Nicholson, John (account), Curtis Estate etc Carter, Joseph 1821-1823 Ouran, Dr.William 1820-1823 Stevenson, Aaron 1822 Sexton, Filnon 1821-1822, 1823, 18224 Nagtee, John 1820-1821 Scott, Henry (B) 1824 Jan 24
  - African Methodist Episcopal Church of Philadelphia #2, 1820-1824
    Bill and receipts: Curtis, Samuel 1820-1824 Smith and ? 1822,1824 Thomas, Augustus 1823 African M.E.W. Church vs John Nicholson (C) court case African M.E.W. Church vs Augustas Thomas court case Ruben Jarman vs Robert Brown, Trustee, A.M.E.W. Church 1824 Summons: Issac B Baxter, Samuel Curtis, Robert Brown, Augustus Thomas, William Perkins - broadside 1822 Oct 1 Judgments against Scott, Henry - 1821 June 13 - broadside Copy and judgments against G. Daniels, Potts etc 1820, 1821 Mortgage tracing of Henry Scotts residence 1821 June 18, 1824 Judgments in two cases - Edward vs Potts etc Notes - Kane W....to J. Kane Court record of dispute between church and Brown, Scott: evidence, papers, produced admitted for decision 1824 April 28
  - Alden, J. Cox to John K. Kane, 1845 July 28
  - Alexander, Archibald to J.K. Kane, 1850 May 21
  - Alexander, E.B. to John K Kane Jr., 1857 July 4
  - Alexander, George William to Hon. John K. Kane, 1855 November 2
    Copy of Resolutions of The British and Foreign Anti-Slavery Society in reference to incarceration of Passmore Williamson.
  - Almbert, d' to John K Kane, Jr., 1857? July 7
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1857 September 5
  - American Philosophical Society astronomical observatory material, 1841
  - American Philosphical Society to Christian Olrik, 1856 April 18
  - American Philosophical Society dinner for J.R. Poinsett material, 1830 May 3
    List to be invited (4 items). Invitation addressed to C J Ingersoll. Letters from: Bainbridge, Commodore - May 1, May 3; Coxe, D W - undated; DeLancey, Dr. - April 30; Fornel, Col. - April 30; Keating, W.H. - April 22, April 23, April 28, May 1; Kridener, Baron de - May 3; Lloyd, J. - April 24, Undated; Martin, Jacob - April 23; Miller Lt. Col.- May 1; Oliver, Robert - April 27, April 29; Poinsett, Joel R. - April 22; Reed, George O. - May 2; Ronaldson, James - April 22; Wents, John - May 3; Wolf, George - April 21
  - American Philosophical Society, H.D.Gilpin, 1837 December 20
  - American Philosophical Society purchase list, 1830 April 9
    For portraits of Jefferson, et al
  - American Philosophical Society report, 1857 November 20
  - American Philosphical Society Wistar party, 1856 March 4
  - Ammen, Daniel to Judge Kane, 1857 February-1857 April
  - Armstrong, Edward to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1846 February 12
  - Ashmead, George L. to Mr. Struthers, 1841 November 18
  - Ashmead, John W to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1841 November
  - Bache, Alexander Dallas to Bache and John Tyler, 1843
    Letters from: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia; American Philosophical Society; Bartlett, WHC; Central High School, Philadelphia; Davies, Charles; Franklin Institute; Hart, John S.; Kane, J.K.; Nott, Eliph, et al; Olmsted, Denison; Patterson, Robert Maskell; Peirce, Benjamin; Princeton University (J. Henry, et al); Renwick, James; University of New York; Webster, H. Recommending Bache for post in US Coast & Geodetic Survey.
  - Bache, Alexander Dallas, 1844-1858
  - Bache, Alexander Dallas to J.K. Kane, Esq., November 9
  - Bache, Alexander Dallas to John K. Kane, November 17
  - Baldwin, Henry to W.H. Hammett (copy), 1844 February 19
  - Baldy, Peter to Gov. Shunk, 1846 January 12
  - Bancroft, George to John K. Kane, 1844-1846
  - Banks, Thaddeus to John K. Kane, 1846 May 5
  - Barbour, James to John K. Kane, 1826 May 16
  - Barclay, John, 1822 April 25
    Affidavit that Thomas Caldwell attended lectures (photocopy).
  - Barnard, Frederick Augustus Porter, 1858 January 21
  - Barr, Daniel to J.K. Kane, Esq., 1845 March 3
  - Barry, William T. to J.K. Kane, Esq., 1831 September-1833 May
  - Bartram, John and James Bartram, 1807 March-1808 March
    Account with Nathan Jones.
  - Bartram, John-Bond to Margaret Robberts, 1804 April 29
  - Bartram, John-Estate-auditor J.K. Kane's request, 1822 Sept 9
  - Bartram, John-Estate-Ann B. Carr, Undated
    Claim for wages.
  - Bartram, John-Estate-claimant's statement, Undated
  - Bartram, John-Estate-executors, 1822 May 2
  - Bartram, John-Estate-executors of first hearing (copy), Undated
  - Bartram, John-Estate-hearing of case, 1822 May-September
  - Bartram, John-Estate-inventory, 1812 May 25
  - Bartram, John-Estate-Nathan Jones, 1798-1799
  - Bartram, John-Estate-Nathan Jones, 1796 September 28-1810 April 27 (Box Oversize)
  - Bartram, John-Estate-Nathan Jones, 1800-1811
  - Bartram, John-Estate-Nathan Jones, Undated
  - Bartram, John-Estate-John K. Kane, auditor, 1822 April 30
  - Bartram, John-Estate-letters Testamentiary and John Bartram's will, 1813 January 6
  - Bartram, John-Estate-meeting by F.E. Brewster, 1822 April 26
  - Bartram, John-Estate-J.B. Norbury to F.E. Brewster, 1822 April 27
  - Bartram, John-Estate-notes, Undated
  - Bartram, John-Estate-settlement, 1821 November 26
  - Bartram, John-Lease to William Bartram and Robert Carr, 1809 December 1
  - Bayard, J.N. to R.M. Lewis, 1830 April 30
  - Bearly, N., et al to F.R. Shunk, 1845 December 23
  - Beaufort, Sir Francis to H. Grinnell, 1857 March 12
  - Beckham, A. to David Hartz, 1845 April 28
  - Beidman, D. to E.K. Price, 1856 December 27
  - Bell, John A. to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1846 February 3
  - Benedict, E.C. to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1850 May 16
  - Bennett, Lorenzo T. to Dr. Hawks, 1853 April 5
  - Bernstorff to Jacob Sperry, 1823 July 6
  - Berrell, Jeremiah to Hon. John K. Kane, 1846 May 14
  - Bethune, George W. to Judge Kane, 1854 December 28
  - Bethune, G.W. to R. Dunglison, 1858 February 23
  - Betts, Samuel to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1847 April 20
  - Beven, Matthew L. to Hon. J.K. Kane (with receipts), 1844-1848
  - Biddle, J. Williams to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1845 December-1846 January
  - Biddle, Thomas to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1845 June 2
  - Bigler, William to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1855 May-1858 January
  - Bills, receipts, etc., 1854
  - Binns, John to John K. Kane Esq., 1845-1846
  - Binns, John to J. Randall, 1846 July 2
  - Birckhead, P.E. to John K. Kane, Esq., 1845 June 20
  - Birckhead, P.E. to Jacob Snider, Jr., 1845 June 20
  - Black, Charles A. to John K. Kane, Esq., 1846
  - Black, Samuel W. to Hon. John K. Kane, 1846 July 13
  - Blackman, M.S. to Hon. John K. Kane; to Mr. Wharton, Esq., 1845-1846
  - Blackman, Samuel A. to John K Kane, Esq., 1845 September 30
  - Blankman, Edmon to Hon. John K. Kane and Robert C. Greir, 1848 August 30
  - Bonham, J. Willis, et al to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1845 June 21
  - Bowen, Charles to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1841 January 12
  - Bowman, George W. to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1846 October 24
  - Boyle, John to Hon. John K. Kane, 1833 August 28
  - Bradford, Eliza to Gov. Shunk, 1845 September 20
  - Bradford, Thomas to John K. Kane Esq., 1841 October-1841 December
  - Bradford, Thomas to William G. Leiper, 1841 September 30
  - Bradley, Ravenel to J.K. Kane, 1857 September 9
  - Brady, Francis E., 1845 June 28
    Motion for deposition of witnesses.
  - Brandt, Joseph to Mr. Thomas, 1796 June 19
    General note
    Removed by Mr. T.C. Cope - 1969 November 11
  - Brandywine, U.S. frigate, 1843-1845
    See: Parker, F.A. Log of the U.S. frigate Brandywine; Logbook #7.
  - Brazer, I. to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1845 September 15
  - Breese, Sidney to Hon. John J. Kane, 1846 June 17
  - Bridges, S.A. to John K. Kane Esq., 1845 September 26
  - Bridges, S.A. to W.J. Leiper, 1844 November 2
  - Briggs, G. to George Stephenson, 1857 April 2
  - Brisbin, John to Hon. John K. Kane, 1845 November 4
  - Brooke, Charles W. to Francis Wharton, 1845 January 8
  - Brooke, James M. to Evan Thomas, 1825 April 27
  - Brown, A.E. to John K. Kane Esq., 1846 February 1
  - Brown, B. to John K. Kane, Esq., 1836 June 13
    Written in Senate Chamber, Washington DC.
  - Brown, B., Undated
    Autograph - franking privilege
  - Brown, David Paul to John K. Kane, Esq., 1846 June
  - Brown, David Paul to Struthers & Son, 1841 March 15
  - Brown, R. to Hon. John K. Kane, 1845 March-1846 February
  - Browne, John C. to J.P. Green, 1857 September 26
  - Browne, Peter A. to John K. Kane Esq., 1845 May
    Includes letter from G.M. Dallas to Peter Browne, dated 1845 June 2.
  - Buchanan, Andrew J. to J.K. Kane Esq., 1846 April 9
  - Buchanan, James to John K. Kane, Esq., 1831-1844
    Letters from President James Buchanan dated: 1831 November 15; 1836 February 26; 1839 October 5; 1839 October 7; 1840 December 13; 1841 September 14; 1844 July 1; 1844 September 30.
  - Burnside, James to Col. James Page; to Hon. John K. Kane, 1845 April 1,1846 Feb 28
  - Butler, Pierce to John K. Kane, Esq., 1846 June 11
  - Cadwalader, John to John K. Kane, Esquire, 1832 November-1838 October
  - Cadwalader, Thomas to Jomingo De Gioconria, 1853 October 4
  - Cadwalader, T. to John K. Kane Esq., 1835 April 29
  - Cadwalader, Thomas, Gen. to Hon. John K. Kane, 1845-1846
  - Cadwel, M. D. to J.P. Green, 1858 August 23
  - Caldwell, John to Thomas Caldwell, 1845 September 15
  - Caldwell, Dr.Thomas, 1821-1828
    Letters from Lavinia Sinclaire, William Caldwell, John Finlay.
  - Calhoun, John C., Undated
    Address leaf.
  - Callahan, Williams, et al to Hon. John K. Kane, 1845 December 16
  - Cameron, Simon to Jesse R. Burden, 1846 June 16
  - Camp, Enoch Ely to President M. van Buren, 1840 July 13
  - Campbell, George Tucker to J.K. Kane Esq., 1845-1846
  - Campbell, H. to W. J. Leiper, Undated
  - Campbell, Hugh to Hon. John K. Kane, 1846 June-1857 April
  - Campbell, Thomas P. to John K. Kane, Esq., 1846 April 21
  - Campener, A. to G.M. Dallas, 1841 March 8
  - _______ to Benjamin Carr, 1825 December 21
  - Carr, Robert to Francis E. Brewster, 1822 January 17
  - Cass, Lewis to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1849-1857
  - Cass, Lewis to George Plitt, 1850 September 20
  - Chambers, M. to David Paul Brown, 1846 June 1
  - Chandler, Joseph R. to Hon. John K. Kane, 1848 March-1857 December
  - Chapman, Henry to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1858 January 28
  - Chase, T.B. to W.H. Weaver, 1849-1850
  - Chauncey, Charles to John K. Kane, Esq., 1829-1831
  - Chew, A.S. to John K. Kane, Esq., 1839 February 23
  - Chew, Anne S.P. to Mr. Kane, 1845 August 18
  - Childs, George W.to J.K. Kane, 1858 January 13
  - Christie, Stuart to Robert Taylor, 1849 April 19
  - Clark, J.G. to J.K. Kane, 1845 October
  - Cochran, Michael to Hon. John K. Kane, 1846 April 13
  - Collet, Mack M. to J.K. Kane, Esq., 1833 December 30
  - Collins, Samuel P. to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1845 September 25
  - Collis, Charles H.T. to Delphian Cricket Club, 1859 April 8
  - Consaden, James and Company to Robert Taylor, 1849 March 22
  - Constable, Mrs. Alida van Renssalaer Kane to J.K. Kane, Esq., 1834-1858
  - Conwell, Henry, Undated
    Extract from book of Baptisms.
  - Cooper, Patrick Kane to John K. Kane, Judge, 1849 April 3
  - Corbin, John S. to Mary S. Corbin, 1841 July 22
  - Corzell, Lewis S. to John K. Kane, Esq., 1846
  - Crabbe, William H. to Hon. John K. Kane, 1856 December 17
  - Cracroft, G.A. to Hon. John K. Kane, 1845 December 8
  - Cracroft, G.A. to F.R. Shunk, 1845 January 7
  - Craig, Andrew C., 1862 January 20
    Receipt.
  - Crano, William J. to Gov. F.R. Shunk, Undated
  - Creacraft, E.G. to John K. Kane, Esq., 1846 February 6
  - Cresson, Mr. to _______, 1856 November 1
  - Cresswell, Harry to Mrs. Eliza Leiper, 1853 April 5
  - Cresswell, John to Hon. John K. Kane, 1846 May 21
  - Cromley, S. to John K. Kane, Esq., 1841 June 9
  - Crozer, John P. to Hon. J.K. Kane, 1856 December 9
  - Crump, G.W. to John Kane, Esq., 1841 November 5
  - Culbertson, S.D. to John K. Kane, Esq., 1862 April 25
  - Cuyler, Theodore to John Kane, Esq., 1845 October 6
  - Da Costa, Jacob Mendez to Bourghelly, 1857? May 20
  - Dade, L.A. to "Dear Sir", 1849 December 10
  - Dallas, George Mifflin to John K. Kane, 1836-1857, undated
  - Damon, Pardon to J.K. Kane, Esq., 1845 April 31
  - Dana, Richard R., Jr. to J.R. Ingersoll, 1847 January 6
  - Darsie, George to J.K. Kane, Esq., 1846
    Letters dated: 1846 February 5; 1846 February 10; 1846 February 19.
  - Davis, John, 1823 May 6
    Certification of Thomas Caldwell. See also: Merritt, George
  - Davis, William H. and Edward Shippen to John K. Kane, Esq., 1846 February 9
  - Dawson, M.L. to T.L. Kane, 1857 May 20
  - Delaware Coal Company to J.K. Kane, Esq., 1846
  - Democracy of Tennessee to Hon. John K. Kane, 1844 June 17
    Committee invitation.